Last night I watched a movie.
Now I do watch movies. This is not my
typical movie. I've told you that I like
movies where they start by running then
I know ah bas this is going to be a good
movie. This is not one of those. Okay,
this was not one of those. It's one of
those soapy movies that uh comes from
the 1970s.
And those of you who were, you know,
adult at that point can remember the
movie title because it was called um let
me let me remember this love story
back in the 70s
and it's about a boy meet girl.
It defined a generation of Americans
growing up and their understanding of
marriage.
It's a tearjerker.
Completely. Now, the interesting thing
is when you watch these sorts of movies
with my wife, she's completely dry eyed.
I'm I'm the one who's really
I'm the one who's crying as as we're
watching the movies. It's a tearjerker.
Completely captured Hollywood's
aspirations and definitions of love and
what love should be and marriage and
what marriage should be. It's a story of
two university students
who were from polar opposites. One was a
rich um privileged polished indulged
young man and the other was a very
strongheaded
um you know girl uncultured coming from
a different area or a different part of
society. They met in university. They
fell in love. They caught it and they
discovered that she was dying
from a rare disease.
By the time you get halfway through the
movie,
you've got a pile of wet tissues next to
you.
It's a typical movie from Hollywood
defining love and marriage.
and it pulls on your heartstrings.
And the scripts of Hollywood's romance
and marriage stories are almost always
the same. Boy meets girl. Initially,
there's some sort of tension. And in
this case, the boy's parents did not
like the girl because she had so no
social standing. Then they discover one
another and they fall in love. And then
it's sunsets and romantic dinners. And
then there's tragedy and some and and
some sort of brokenness. And after that
there's deep sadness that sets in. And
then there are problems that need to be
solved. And then they marry and they
have pure joy and bliss. And they drive
off into the sunset and live happily
ever after.
Any
of you who's been married for any length
of time knows that's not going to
happen.
It's an illusion that Hollywood sells.
It's a false narrative.
The reality is far different.
Marriage is waking up in the morning to
the bad breath of your spouse.
And nobody told you about that. Not even
in the premarital counseling classes.
Marriage, you do not kiss your your your
spouse before they go into the bathroom
and they flush their mouth.
Marriage is puffed up faces in the
morning. It's dreary eyes. It's sleep.
You know the the the salt thingy that
that crystallizes in the night at the
corner of your eyes. You have to flash
your face and wash it. Marriage is
cooking bland meals half the time and
burnt offerings the other half. Marriage
is nappies and conflicts and arguments
over money and tears and anger and
sometimes being bullied or bullying the
other and shouting them down and feeling
it's not fair and labor in the home is
not shared fairly.
There is the dream,
but this is the reality.
When my wife and I got married and went
off to our honeymoon, um we say these
words to one another. We were young, we
were in love, we had not yet experienced
the reality of marriage. And we say this
to one another. Today I married my best
friend
and we lived happily ever after.
Never happened.
I remember being at the dinner table one
time and uh our three older children
were born and the the the the last one
at that point who is now has been
married for two years um just gave us a
grandson two weeks ago. But the last
one, you know, um was sitting at the
table and we asked her, uh, "What is
your best friend's name?" And she said,
"My best friend." And she was in
kindergarten, I think it was. "My best
friend is called, you know, Susan." And,
uh, we said, "She's in your class." Yes.
Yes. And she told us about her best
friend. And then she went on to say,
"And and and and mommy, my bestest
friend is called Janet." Okay. I didn't
know there was a best friend and a
bestest friend. And she told us about
that. Then she turned to us and she
asked us, you know, and she asked our
mother, "Uh, mommy, who is your best
friend?" And, uh, my wife said, "My best
friend is my husband. It's daddy." And
she looked at her mom and she said,
"Daddy can't be your best friend. You're
married to him.
Except maybe in rural and traditional
societies,
50% of marriages largely around the
world, particularly in urban centers,
end up in divorce.
That's one out of every two marriages.
And last time I checked the statistics
of our country here at the registra of
marriages, most couples divorce in their
seventh and eighth year.
But the story of those seventh or eight
years that lead to divorce began in the
second year when the marriage died.
And in the third year, one spouse or the
other filed for divorce.
And then our courts and our legal system
took four years to dissolve the
marriage. And so in the eighth year is
when they finally have gotten rid of the
other partner.
But the marriage actually died in the
second year.
And from everything I know, divorce is
very very hard
in every way you look at it. Some
couples will say, "We decided to get
divorce because it's better for the
children." It is never better for the
children. And study after study after
study has shown that the children of
divorce are devastated for the next 2030
years
and it is never better for the children.
They never did consult the children and
ask them, "Children, what would you like
for mommy and daddy to separate so that
you can live with them alternatively?
One week with this one, one week with
the other or that even though we have
problems and you sometimes hear our
voices through the bedroom door, would
you prefer that we stay together?" I
think almost every time except in the
case where a spouse is brutalizing the
children in almost every case the
children would choose we want you to
stay together. It is never better for
the children.
Divorce tears you apart on the inside.
It crushes you. Your life is filled with
tears and depression. Friends distance
themselves from you. If you do become
divorced, it makes one feel like a
failure, as though you failed in life,
as though everyone can see that you're
divorced and abandons you and moves
away. Divorce rips open the heart. And
no matter how hard you try, it's tears
and tears and tears of brokenness and
pain. It comes to define you over the
next 7 to 10 years of healing because it
takes 7 to 10 years to heal from a
divorce.
And there are bouts of denial and bouts
of pain and bouts of self-lame. And
healing is long and slow. your dreams
are crushed and you know that you will
never fall in love again because you
never want to go back into that space.
The reality of this possible eventuality
in marriage is a far cry from the movies
we see from Hollywood or from Nollywood
or from Bollywood.
whether they're made in India or Nigeria
or in the US. I have a close friend who
got married to his very close and dear
friend. Their courtship was beautiful
and romantic. They were out of
university. They were agemates. We
watched them. They were both delightful
people. And when they came together,
found each other, we thought, "What a
good coupling. What a beautiful thing."
We celebrated their love for each other
and we all used to cool and swoon at uh
you know their romantic uh advances
towards each other as he treated her
tenderly and gave her gifts. We all
wished as young Christian men that we
could do likewise when the time would
come for us. But when my time came for
courtship, I was too broke to copy him
because I was trying to pay my way
through theological college. I used to
be a photographer taking photos of
weddings. I would collect the money I'm
given and go and deposit it as part of
my school fees. And it was hard getting
through theological college. My father
had told me, "I've educated you to your
first degree and now you want to become,
you know, a man of God." and my support
and my sponsorship ends here. You go now
and you do your heart's delight. And so
he did not um support me through
theological college. And my wife to be
was too broke because
she would finance my book fund and my
study purchases. So our romance was
played out in Uhuru Park near Serena
Hotel. You know that Kakono Serena Hotel
and what romantic meals we had were
Mandazi and Fanta?
When my friend got married, it was a
fancy and flashy wedding. But five years
later, they were in divorce proceedings.
We his friends couldn't understand why.
They had had a courtship worth envying,
and we knew that they were set for life.
And yet here they were headed for
divorce. It was from him that I ever
heard this phrase that you may have
heard me say, "Marriage is hard and then
you die."
It just seems so cynical and so
defeist, but marriage is hard and then
you die. That's unfair.
The Hollywood version of marriage did
not work out for them. You see,
Hollywood has sold you a lie.
Hollywood has heightened the illusion
that the purpose of marriage is romance
and romantic feelings. I've heard in
Hollywood movies, people say dumb things
like, "I loved you and married you
because you make me laugh.
They're making you laugh. Well, that
doesn't last long after you get married.
If you want to keep mar I mean laughing,
don't marry that person. They'll keep
you laughing.
Here's the thing with marriage and with
everything beautiful that God created in
the Garden of Eden. Marriage is broken.
broken because it was touched by the sin
of Adam and Eve.
When God finds the man in the Garden of
Eden and asks Adam, "What is this that
you have done?" Adam doesn't take
responsibility for his sin.
Instead, he puts the blame on Eve.
Genesis 3 and:e 12. The woman you gave
me, the woman you put here with me, she
gave me some of that fruit to eat. Go
ask her and settle things with her. This
was Adam shifting the blame.
And because of his sin and the sin of
Eve, marriage was broken from the very
first. When God punished the woman, he
said, "I will make your pains in
childbirth very severe. With painful
labor, you will give birth to children.
Broken
labor pains are said to be some of the
most severe pains known to man.
Men have no idea what it takes to birth
a child
and the pain that a woman goes through
as she delivers a baby.
And yet true to what God said, your
desire will be for your husband and she
goes back and she gets pregnant again
and she has another baby and she goes
through. You think once and never again.
Now I know I know most in fact all the
husbands here have no clue what it took
for your wife to give you that baby.
You men who have just finished man
enough.
I hope one of the studies was on the
pain of labor so that you can love your
wife for the children she's given you. I
know even though I'm not a woman I know
the labor pains and you're asking how do
you know? I'll tell you how I know.
When our first child was born, she came
early at 7 months. She was a premy and
we rushed to the hospital and the doctor
said it's too early. you can't, she
can't, you can't deliver now. And so
they put my wife on the drip to reverse
the labor pains, to stop the labor
pains. And for about 8 hours, they fed
her whatever they were pumping into her
to stop the labor pains. But this child
was determined to come and the labor
pains would not stop. And so after that
period of time, the nurses said, "This
child is going to come one way or the
other." And so let's enable the the
process. So they reversed the medicine
they were giving her so that now it
would enhance the labor pains. Oh yeah,
my wife for 8 hours she's been getting
medicine to stop delivering and now they
have changed and they're giving her
medicine to start delivering and I was
there as a concerned husband. I love
this woman. I have seen what she's going
through. So I made the mistake of taking
her hand in my palm and stroking her and
saying
you know it's okay it's going to be okay
and etc. And the labor pains began and
she started going
and I had not reckoned that when she
does this she squeezes on the hand and
I'm going
I kid you not. We delivered that child
together.
I know what it's like to deliver.
God's second punishment to the woman
because of her sin was, "Your desire
will be for your husband and he will
rule over you."
broken.
Because in many marriages,
men rule over their wife with harsh,
devastating, demeaning power that
sometimes brutalizes them.
To the man, his punishment in Genesis 3
was, "Cursed is a ground because of you.
through painful toil you will eat from
it all the days of your life and it will
produce thorns and thistles.
It will produce weeds
for you and you will eat the plants of
the field by the sweat of your brow. You
will eat your food until you return to
the ground. But ladies,
if you walk around shambers today, who
do you find in the shamba?
It's women.
Somehow the man, even though he was
punished, found a way to trick his wife
so that she goes to the shamba and she
labors and she sweats and he eats.
Marriage is broken. To have a happy
fulfilling marriage takes a tremendous
amount of work. And Hollywood says that
marriage is fun and happy and
fulfilling. But the reality is that 90%
of the marriages you know are mediocre
and there is little joy in them. They
are hard and uninspiring
unless you change your perspective on
marriage and put in the hard work. What
do I mean?
The first hard work you put into
marriage is this to always remember that
marriage is not about you.
The second is that marriage is not about
my personal self fulfillment.
And the third is that you are not the
center and the focus of your marriage.
And your happiness and your personal
fulfillment is not what marriage is
about. There is no other verse in
scripture that puts it better than
Philippians chapter 1 and verse 27 where
Paul writes and he says whatever happens
in your marriage he doesn't use those
words in your marriage but whatever
happens conduct yourselves in a manner
worthy of the gospel of Christ.
Ladies, listen to the first purpose of
marriage as given to us in Ephesians
chapter 5 and verse 22-33.
Wives, submit yourselves to your
husbands
as you do to the Lord. That's your
standard, your measure.
For the husband is the head of the wife
as Christ is the head of the church, his
body of which he is a savior. Now, as a
church submits to Christ, so also wives
should submit to their husbands in
everything.
And you say, "But it's not fair."
And God says, "It's not about fairness.
It's about obedience.
Will you do it for me who you call your
savior because you love me?" And you
say, "What if he takes advantage of me
and makes me into a doormat?" And God
says, "I'll deal with him as I choose,
but will you obey me?
Not because marriage is supposed to be
50/50,
but because I want your 100% obedience."
And you say, "But he's not obeying you.
He's cruel and he's harsh and he is he
is mean." And God says, "Maybe,
but you don't obey me because he obeyed
me. You obey me because I am your Lord
and your Savior, and I'm asking you to
obey me."
And you say, "But I won't be happy and
fulfilled." And God says, "It was never
about your self-fulfillment and your
personal happiness. It was always about
me and obedience.
Wives, you submit
not because your husband makes you happy
and is a tall, dark, handsome man you
had dreamt of and Hollywood had promised
you, but because God has asked you to
submit.
And this is a hard teaching.
And we all have an opinion on that. And
it's not fair,
but it's what God has asked of you as
his child.
If there is any joy in submission,
it's that you have obeyed God.
Whatever happens, conduct yourself in a
manner that glorifies God, that you
obeyed him. even if your rights were
denied.
Remember Paul's words in Galatians
chapter 2 and verse 20. I have been
crucified with Christ. And it is no
longer I who lives but Christ who lives
in me. And the life I now live in the
body I live by faith in the son of God
who loved me, denied himself of his
rights and his personal happiness, and
he gave himself up for me.
The cross was not about my personal
fulfillment.
Jesus died on the cross
in obedience to God.
There is so much in scripture that calls
you to a life of dying to self
and marriage is one of them.
It's not about you.
It's about obedience.
Wise in marriage, your mirror to
submission is what Christ has done.
His submission to to God cost him
everything,
even death.
And now he's asking you to do that for
him. Even if it means submission will
cost you, your personal fulfillment.
Your dreams will die. You will not have
that picture perfect Hollywood marriage.
That too will die on the altar of
obedience to God. And yes, for those of
you who are not yet married, you want to
take two and ask yourself, do I really
want to get married?
Because once you do tie the bond of
marriage,
there is no out.
The couple who counseledled us when we
were going for premarital counseling
with my wife told us picture marriage as
going into a room that has a window and
a door and you have the key in your hand
and you lock the door. You walk up to
the window and you throw the key out of
the window
far away never to be found again. And
then for the rest of your life you live
in that room with your spouse. You
better be friends cuz it's going to be a
long time.
There is no out.
And so if you're not yet married,
think twice whether you really want to
get married because when you do, it's
about obedience to Christ.
husbands.
Christ doesn't just speak to the wife.
He speaks to the husband also. And he
says, "Husbands, love your wives
just as Christ loved the church and gave
himself up for her to make her holy,
cleansing her by the washing with water
through the word, and to present her as
a radiant church without stain or
wrinkle or any other blemish, but holy
and blameless. In the same way, husbands
ought to love their wives as their own
bodies. He who loves his wife loves
himself. After all, no one ever hated
his own body, but they feed and care for
their body just as Christ does for the
church. For you are members of his body.
What is God saying to the husband in
this passage? I believe there are three
things that God says to the husband. And
the first is this. Love your wife
just as Christ loved the church. Again,
the standard of our love in marriage is
not that everything is okay and we're in
a good space now. The standard of our
love for our spouse in marriage is what
Christ did in his love for the church.
And you've got to agree with me with all
the shenanigans that you see in churches
today, all the heresies, all the ugness,
ugliness, all the abuse of power. This
bride is not a very beautiful bride.
But Christ loved her and went to the
cross for her. It's not your wife's
behavior and the things she says and how
she, you know, puts you down and etc,
etc. You got married
and it's about obedience
to God. Love your wife as Christ loved
the church. Your standard of love is not
your friends. It's not Hollywood. It's
not the books you read. It's not, you
know, what your wife does. Your standard
of love is Christ and his love for the
church.
Be willing to lay down your life for
her.
Christ's call on your life is that you
die
to yourself and you live for him. Not
even live for your wife, but live for
him. That's what obedience for the
husband is about.
So
Christ hadn't yet told you to take a
knife and slit your throat because his
marriage is going downhill. No, no, no,
no, no. That's not possible. He says
washing her clothes is not dying.
And cooking for her and going to the
kitchen is not dying.
Changing the baby diapers is not dying.
dealing with the poop is not dying.
Why is it that we expect the women to do
this but the husbands never enter into
that space?
Well, you know, my child is a daughter
and so I have to give some privacy and I
can't change diapers. Well, what about
your son? Your wife changes your son's
diapers. Why doesn't she say, "Well,
he's a boy and you know we need to
separate the genders. So, you know, you
change the diapers of the boys and we'll
change I'll change the diapers of the
girls.
Okay, ladies, you can sign up to my fan
club after this.
[Laughter]
Husbands who don't die to self and live
for Christ by living for their wives end
up having mediocre marriages.
You don't change diapers
because you enjoy doing it.
You change diapers because Christ has
asked you to die to yourself
and to love your wife and serve her.
You serve her, cook for her, tend to
her, care for her because Christ is your
measure of love and not Hollywood's
romance and candlelight dinners and
personal fulfillment.
Even if you married a witch,
you chose her and you married her.
Stop mourning and groaning now.
And then it says, "Husbands,
make her holy.
Cleanse her and present her as radiant.
present her in the best light possible
without stain or wrinkle or any other
blemish.
Why is it in marriages there is always a
you know money enough to buy a
MercedesBenz SUV for the husband but
there's only enough money to buy her
vits.
Ever turn to your husband and say,
"Yeah, actually, you know, like why?"
Let her drive the Mercedes-Benz SUV. You
drive the Vitz.
And yes, if you don't want that job
description, then take two and don't get
married in the first place.
If you do get married, then this is what
you have signed up for to love her, make
her holy, cleans her, and present her as
radiant.
Let her walk with Christ and her
passions and obedience to God mirror
your own walk with Christ and your
passion and obedience to God. We are
called as men
to be the priests in the home.
And you don't delegate that to your
wife.
You lead
your prayers
and your spiritual rhythms as a family
and your passion for God.
It is an act of obedience.
Put aside your personal happiness. God
would say and do it in obedience to me.
And then thirdly,
let your marriage be a testimony of the
Christ you love. Jesus said, I'm asking
you to do this in verse 29. After all,
no one ever hated his own body, but they
feed and care for their bodies just as
Christ does the church.
Your marriage is a witness to a world in
need of a savior.
And if you are to say you love Christ,
you follow Christ, you're even an elder
in the church, you preach on Sundays,
but then they see you're horrible to
your wife at home, and you brutalize
her, the one cancels the other.
But if they see your marriage is so an
African is so biblical, you love and
care for and cherish your spouse,
then they can begin to believe about
this Christ that you profess.
Your marriage is a testimony to the
world around you and it is a testimony
to God of your love for him.
Nothing in Ephesians chapter 5 talks
about self fulfillment and personal
happiness.
It talks about obedience.
And the mirror or the image that we are
to use as a standard in our marriage is
Christ in his love for the church and
his willingness to die for her. divorce
because you don't have self fulfillment
and personal happiness in your marriage.
Divorce is a shortcut
of disobedience
to Christ,
seeking to have your own way.
Now, those sound like harsh words, but
true words. I believe that there are
only three instances in the Bible where
God says sadly yes, divorce. And the
first is abandonment when the one spouse
walks away with no intentions of ever
coming back. And the second is cruelty
where one person brutalizes the other.
And the third is infidelity.
Short of that, you are in this for life.
And divorce is a shortcut to
disobedience
so that you can pursue personal
happiness with someone else.
I'll come back to these later on in this
series. But anything short of these
three, Jesus stay says, "Stay in
obedience to me and fulfill the vow that
you made." Wives, serve your husband.
Husbands, love your wives because you
love me. Even if you yourself choose or
chose and married a witch
and will never know happiness in your
marriage, stay and love her. You made
your bed, sleep in it.
The chance you have to say, "Hey, this
one is a witch is before you go to the
altar." So, young men, be very careful.
And young ladies, he looks nice, but you
need to know what's happening on the
inside. Be very careful. So, let me
conclude.
I want to have time to cover the other
two reasons for marriage. But I wanted
to begin with this one because marriage
is not about personal happiness. It's
about obedience. Once you are married,
obey the Lord.
Someone here has been wrestling and
entertaining thoughts of divorce
and escape from their difficult
marriage. And in very clear words, I
message to you God's desire for you in
saying stay
for his sake and obey him.
There may be somebody here who can
clearly hear what God is speaking to
them
and they need to stop focusing on
themselves and what they're getting out
of their marriage.
And this is God's word to you today.
There may be somebody else here, a young
man, a young woman who just heard God
say, "This is not the person that I have
for you." Even though you feel that
you're so in love, it doesn't matter.
Listen to your doubts and listen to my
voice and bring this relationship to an
end. Because if you do go ahead and get
married, I will call you to be faithful
to the vow that you made and to obey me
as your God and stay in your marriage.
Maybe there's a husband here who's
committing adultery even now. And it may
be physical adultery on the one hand or
it may be emotional adultery
that even when you make love to your
wife in your heart of hearts you're
calling another name your wife is called
Susan but your heart is saying oh Janet
Janet Janet and one day it will slip out
and God is saying,
"Stop.
You made a vow to your wife. You married
her. Love her. There is no other.
I can see your wondering heart. I can
see that you're about to dishonor me,
but stop and love your wife and stay in
your marriage."
And there may be a woman here who is
already in an affair because your lover
seems to give you the attention and the
fulfillment that your husband doesn't
give you. And God is saying to you
today, you're disobeying me.
Even though you say you love me, stop
and go back to your first love
until death do you part.
And so I want us to pray and I'm going
to invite two people up here to lead us
in a word of prayer. And the first is of
course Pastor Sam Odero works with a
man. He prayed a little earlier but
pastor Sam if I could invite you to come
and just pray for those who know God has
spoken to them today and something needs
to change. Something needs to stop.
Something new and beautiful needs to
begin. That is obedience to Christ. But
I'm also going to ask Rei Awa to come
forward. She's involved in our prayer
ministry here at the chapel,
particularly the morning vigil and
particularly the midweek Wednesday
prayer meeting. And I'm going to ask her
to come. Um Reie, I know you. I know
your husband. Um,
and I want you to pray, Reie, for the
women here who are wrestling
with brokenness because their marriage
is broken. And Sam, if you could pray
for the men, that they would stand and
be faithful
to the partner that they chose until
death do them part. And guys, don't go
and commit suicide. until death do you
part. Would you lead us in prayer?
Wow.
Let us believe and pray.
Amen. Just focus on God. Let us
surrender to God. Heavenly Father, this
this morning we are challenged
Lord. We have no words.
We find it difficult. But here we are as
men. There are men amongst us who have
chosen the wrong path. There are those
that have neglected their wives. There
are those that have not loved their
wives as they should have. And Lord, I
stand here as a representation of the
men. I pray that would you have mercy on
us. Would you have mercy on me as a man?
Help me Lord to love my wife, to stand
for my wife. I pray Lord that may you
help every man in this congregation
today
to think deeply about their relationship
with their wives and to love them as
Christ loved the church. You've reminded
us that is about obedience to you, Lord
Jesus. It is not about our
self-interests. It's not about how we
feel, but it's about obeying you,
Father. And so Lord, I pray that as men
that have had this message today, we'll
stand up and we'll own up and we'll do
the right thing and that is to love our
wives because we are obeying you, the
Lord Jesus Christ. Father, I pray that
may your spirit help us, oh God, that we
may stand, that we may be counted upon
as faithful men, that will keep our
marriages, that will keep our marriage
beds pure to the glory of your name. men
that will sanctify our wives, that will
encourage our wives, that will support
our wives in every situation, oh God.
Father, be glorified and exalted today.
And I pray that may you hold our hands,
oh God, and take us in every step of our
marriages that your name will be
glorified. Your name will be exalted in
our in our marriages and in our lives
now and forever more. In Jesus name I
pray. Amen. Our dear heavenly father, we
come before your throne of grace with
thanksgiving in our hearts. Oh Lord,
we're careful to say thank you for the
gift of life you've given unto us. Oh
God, thank you for your word that has
come so deeply into our hearts today. Oh
God, I stand before you, Lord. I
represent uh the women, the wives, the
wives to be. Oh Lord, Father, we come
before you, Lord, with a broken and
contrite spirit. for a broken and
contrite spirit you will not despise.
And we ask that Lord, would you have
mercy in our lives? Oh God, forgive us
for the sin of murmuring and
complaining. Almighty King of glory,
forgive us, oh God, for where we have
wronged and fallen short of your glory.
Forgive us, oh God, for we have not done
it in in honor of your word. Forgive us
for harboring those thoughts of divorce
and wanting a way out. Oh God, forgive
us. Oh Lord, for we have not seen where
we have erided ourselves as women and as
wives. Oh God, forgive us, oh Lord, for
not being able to be supportive to our
husbands and our spouses. Oh God, have
mercy upon us. Almighty King of glory,
Father, forgive us where we have made it
all about ourselves and our personal
interests and what makes us happy, oh
God, and not obeying your command or
what pleases you, oh God. Forgive us
where we have just looked about I myself
and me, oh God. What do I want? What
makes me happy, oh God? And why he's not
doing this for me, oh God? And I've not
we've not asked ourselves. I've not
asked myself what should I do to make
him happy to be there for him as your
servant. Oh God, forgive us, oh God,
where we've not taken our position in
the home to pray and to call upon you,
to invite you into our spaces like the
virtuous woman. Oh God, forgive us, oh
God, for the things that we have done
knowingly and unknowingly to pull down
our marriages. Oh God, forgive us. Oh
God, for we've not seen the devil
masquerading as the angel of light. Oh
God, in our in our friends at work, in
wherever, oh God, who are telling us the
things that we yearn to hear that our
spouses don't tell us, oh God, forgive
us, oh God, for Lord God, we have fallen
short of your glory. And we're crying
out to you. We approach your throne of
grace boldly that we may obtain mercy.
And we pray, have mercy upon us, oh God.
Have mercy upon our marriages that are
crumbling, oh God. Have mercy upon us
for harboring the thoughts of divorce
and looking for a way out. Any little
opportunity to say, "I'm done with this.
Forgive us, oh God." And we pray the
Lord, oh God, in your judgment, would
you remember mercy, oh God? I pray,
Father, on behalf of wives to be, oh
God, who are walking this journey. And
we invite you the Lord. We may walk this
journey with you before we say I do. We
will hear your still small voice telling
us this is the way. Walk here in it.
Father, we pray for our marriages and we
pray that you may come and have your way
in the place where it is broken and
we're looking like nothing is working.
The Bible says, "Is there anything too
difficult for you?" We come to the point
of cross, oh God, and we surrender our
marriages to you, oh God. May you help
us you whose mercies are new every
morning. Oh God pray that Lord oh God
you may have mercy upon us and help us
take us back to the heart of worship for
it's all about you. Reignite the love in
our lives oh God in our marriages. Oh
God give us a spark yet again. Help us
to come to the point of obedience. Oh
God forgive us for selfcenteredness. Oh
God as a family as women. Oh God as
wives. Oh God, forgive us and have mercy
upon us. Help us take our position,
Almighty Father, for you've called us
for such a time as this. And as we come
before you, Lord, we are asking you to
order our steps. Almighty Father, may
your word continuously be a lighter unto
our feet and a lamper to our path as we
walk in obedience to your word, as we
desire to hold on to the confession of
our faith. And help us be strong in our
marriage. revive our marriages yet
again. Put that spark in our marriages
yet again. May you hark in our prayers,
the prayers we've made in our closets,
the prayers we've made crying unto you
because none of it is in vain, almighty
father. And we pray that Lord, you may
have your way, have your way in our
lives, have your way in our midst. For
it's in Jesus name we pray.
>> Amen. Amen. And so, Father, go with us.
We need to process what we have heard.
Somehow we need to die to self
that we may obey you.
Help us Lord in Jesus name. Amen. Go
with God's grace. Thank you.